Titouan **Renard**,

Master student in Robotics with a minor in Data Science

© (+41) 79 944 61 65

⊠ titouan.renard@epfl.ch

Q Lausanne, Switzerland

I am student at EPFL currently pursuing a Master of Sciences in Robotics with a minor in Data Science. I am interested in control theory, machine learning and their applications to robotic systems. I also have some experience in student associations and am proficient in French and English.

Education

Ongoing Master in Robotics with a Minor in Data Science, Lausanne, Switzerland

2020-Present
EPFL. STI and IC faculties

Bachelor in Microengineering, Lausanne, Switzerland

2020

EPFL, STI faculty

Bilingual Maturité, Neuchâtel, Switzerland

2016

French-English bilingual high-school education, Lycée Denis de Rougemont, PYAM (Physics and Applied Math)

Experience

Student-Assistant at EPFL, for the courses "Physique Générale 1" (Newtonian Mechanics), "Microinformatique" (basics of embedded systems programming for Microengineering students) and Material Sciences Practicals

Responsable Politique, member of the direction comity of Unipoly (student's association for sustainabily at EPFL), responsible for interactions with stakeholders and EPFL's direction on matters of sustainabily on campus.

2020-2021

Public relations experience, some experience with media and press releases.

Responsible of Events for the 2020 sustainabily week on EPFL campus, Unipoly, Management and coordination of about 30 events on EPFL and UNIL's campuses.

2020

Summer Internship, Birorobotics Lab EPFL, at the Biorobotics Laboratory at EPFL, implementation of a simple vision-based localization system using C++ and OpenCV.

2018

European Youth Parliament, Switzerland

2015-2016

English language public speaking experience.

Skills

Programming, in C, C++, Javascript, Matlab, Python and Scala

Math and Applied Math, Probabilities, Linear Algebra, Calculus, Dynamic System Theory and Control Theory, Signal Processing, Algorithmic Design and Analysis

Physics and Engineering Sciences, Mechanics, Thermodynamics, Electromagnetism, Electronics, Basics of Materials Science

Soft Skills, public speaking, writing and team management learned in the context student associations

Languages

French: Native proficiency **English**: Full proficiency

German: High-School level (B2)